<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>gvsi.github.io/cs371p/</title>
   
   <link>http://gvsi.github.io/cs371p/</link>
   <description>A blog with my progress with CS371p at UT Austin</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> Giovanni Alcantara</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Week 3</title>
	  <link>/cs371p//week-three</link>
	  <author>Giovanni Alcantara</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-09-10T19:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/cs371p//week-three</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h2 id="what-did-i-do-this-past-week">What did I do this past week?</h2>
<p>We’re barely at the beginning of the semester, and time is gradually becoming a very precious resource.</p>

<p>The first project deadline was this week, and I think I handled my priorities very well, having worked on most of the tasks early.</p>

<p>This week we covered pointers and references in C++. It gets very verbose and confusing at times, but as professor Downing said, the key to understanding these concepts really boils down to sitting at your desk and trying it out yourself.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/pointers.png" alt="Relevant " /></p>

<p>This week I’ve also been to the Engineering EXPO. It’s my first carrier fair in the US, and it’s really an event that does not compare to what we have in the UK. Carrier fairs across the pond are of much smaller scale, and it’s mostly an opportunity for employers to publicize their brand, rather than an opportunity to actively hire talent.</p>

<p>It went very well, and managed to get a few interviews lined up for next week. When I didn’t have the chance to achieve something concrete, I still treasured it as an opportunity to talk to employers and practice the art of talking and showing what I’m passionate about.</p>

<p>This week I also had the opportunity to attend a talk by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Robert_Metcalfe">Bob Metcalfe</a> as part of the Longhorn Startup Seminar class I am taking. It was a great talk, and touched on some decisions I have been struggling with: “should I focus on getting a job at a tech company or try to start my own thing?”</p>

<h2 id="whats-in-my-way">What’s in my way?</h2>
<p>Too many things to do. Coursework is taking most of my time. Having a part-time job where I get to code is great, but also very time consuming. Practicing for interviews is also at the top of my priority list, but I haven’t been able to focus on it more than I wanted.</p>

<p>Thankfully, as a Computer Scientist, I tend to keep my social endeavours as little as possible, but it’s helped my sanity to go out and meet some friends.</p>

<h2 id="what-will-i-do-next-week">What will I do next week?</h2>
<p>Next week I will try to find meaning in the things that I do. There are things that I do everyday that I almost take for granted, and want to find happiness and gratitude in the things that I get to do. This has kept me from being overwhelmed by the many things I have to do.</p>

<p>I’ll also try to find a partner for Project 2. I am really keen on working with someone else, so if you’re interested, feel free to <a href="&#109;&#097;&#105;&#108;&#116;&#111;:&#109;&#101;&#064;&#103;&#105;&#111;&#118;&#097;&#110;&#110;&#105;&#097;&#108;&#099;&#097;&#110;&#116;&#097;&#114;&#097;&#046;&#099;&#111;&#109;">contact me</a> and we can talk about it.</p>

<h2 id="tip-of-the-week">Tip of the week</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Meditation. It’s great, and as little as 5 minutes a day helps a lot. <a href="https://www.calm.com/">Calm.com</a> is a great website to get started.</li>
  <li><a href="intern.supply">Intern.supply</a> helps me keep track of which companies have opened applications for 2017 Software Developer Summer Internships.</li>
</ul>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Week 2</title>
	  <link>/cs371p//week-two</link>
	  <author>Giovanni Alcantara</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-09-04T17:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/cs371p//week-two</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h2 id="what-did-i-do-this-past-week">What did I do this past week?</h2>
<p>Last week has been an introductory week, where not much was going on. It’s the end of week two now, and work is already piling up. We dived right into work. Project 1 specifications were released and the submission has been set for next week, new C++ concepts were introduced, new readings are due for next week.</p>

<p>The project is what has taken most of my time this week. Not so much the algorithmic side of it. A great deal of optimizing the code really boils down to a standard dynamic programming problem, with memoization in the form of cache. What really took most of my time is the setting up the infrastructure and the whole suite of tools that accompany the task.</p>

<p>These included setting up the Docker container, writing unit tests with <code class="highlighter-rouge">gtest</code> and acceptance tests, documenting the code for <code class="highlighter-rouge">doxygen</code>, make sure all the targets in the <code class="highlighter-rouge">makefile</code> are working as expected, hooking up <code class="highlighter-rouge">Travis-CI</code> with the repository, keeping the list of Github issues updated, making sure the source files have been formatted with <code class="highlighter-rouge">clang-format</code>.</p>

<p>It’s been a ride, but while reviewing the files for submission I found myself with a wide smile stamped on my face.</p>

<p>In class we have covered the different between <code class="highlighter-rouge">l-values</code> and <code class="highlighter-rouge">r-values</code>, exception handling with a discussion of the advantages and disadvantages between <code class="highlighter-rouge">throw</code>s, error flags in the form global variables or local variables being passed as references.</p>

<h2 id="whats-in-my-way">What’s in my way?</h2>
<p>Me. I’m in my own way.</p>

<p>Working on the project, I’ve been incredibly frustrated when things would not run as expected. Getting all the tools to work is a tedious process, and thinking “Man, I could be working on some other stuff if this thing worked as expected” really gets in my head sometimes.</p>

<p>I also cannot put my computer to sleep when stuff is just not working. I do realize that taking a break helps clear one’s mind, but I often find myself working until “I fix this one thing”, which eventually leads to other things breaking on the way, and being stuck in a vicious cycle.</p>

<p>What I gradually learned to realize is that getting stuck is the only way to learn, and this helped me have a different approach when working.</p>

<h2 id="what-will-i-do-next-week">What will I do next week?</h2>
<p>It’s that period of the year when companies hire for summer internships. Next week I would like to start revising algorithms and data structures.</p>

<h2 id="tip-of-the-week">Tip of the week</h2>
<p>Learn your regular expressions. They’re one thing thing that I constantly find using in one way or another when working on projects or programming assignments. They’re an absolute must know to master find-and-replace in your code and they come in handy for string manipulation. Also, they’re incredibly fun to write. <a href="http://regexr.com/">RegExr</a> can help you build, test and also learn this art.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Week 1</title>
	  <link>/cs371p//week-one</link>
	  <author>Giovanni Alcantara</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-08-27T13:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/cs371p//week-one</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Hello, world!</p>

<p>This is my first class at UT and UTCS, and I could not be happier that CS 371p taught by professor Downing is the one marking this milestone.</p>

<p>To provide context, I am an Exchange student from the University of Edinburgh in Scotland, United Kingdom. I have the great opportunity of spending two semesters here at the University of Texas at Austin.</p>

<p>I see three main benefits to having to document part of my academic experience at UT through this blog:</p>

<ol>
  <li>For <strong>future students considering to take this class</strong>, you can reference this blog and have a more personal, detailed feedback on the course;</li>
  <li>For <strong>prospective exchange students</strong>, you can learn about what the differences in the US education system and why an International Exchange in the USA can open opportunities uniquely available here, home of academic excellence;</li>
  <li>For <strong>me</strong>, I can take a moment every week to reflect on the concepts that I learn this semester, which I am sure would reinforce their overall understanding.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="a-different-approach">A Different Approach</h2>

<h3 id="interactive">Interactive</h3>

<p>I’ll begin by talking about the thing that shocked me the most. <strong>The interactivity of classes</strong>. Back in my home University, most lectures comprise of a lecturer who talks and an audience of students who listens. The flow is unidirectional. There is no interactivity, no dialogue. It’s a passive experience for students.</p>

<p>CS 371p is designed by professor Downing to involve students in class dialogue–the structure of the class promotes discussion, students are challenged with every new concept.</p>

<p>Continuous evaluation is at the heart of the course. Quizzes are scheduled daily and touch on often non-trivial concepts that have been discussed in class. This motivates me to gain a much deeper understanding of the subject, and decreases the chances of falling behind.</p>

<h3 id="social">Social</h3>
<p>As was mentioned in class, Computer Science students are one of the most anti-social groups out there. Paradoxically, development teams in most tech companies are all designed to be collaborative environments. Effective communication is essential in creating the dynamics for the development of successful products.</p>

<p>CS 371p aims to provide an experience that simulates as much as possible a real working environment in an academic setting. An awkward “meet-your-neighbors” moment was forced on us the first minutes of class. Projects were introduced as being meant to be worked on as pairs of students.</p>

<p>This shall be fun.</p>

<h3 id="modern">Modern</h3>
<p>The problem with Computer Science class is, in most of the cases, that material becomes outdated after a few years. Teaching often falls behind the velocity with which new tools, languages, technologies and trends are being released.</p>

<p>The set of development tools that we will be using is standard in the industry. Here are some examples:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong><a href="https://www.docker.com">Docker</a></strong> is now the <em>cool</em> way to build, ship, and run applications for many teams in companies and startups;</li>
  <li>the practice of continuous integration is now an established component of the development process, and having the opportunity to use <strong><a href="https://travis-ci.org/">Travis-CI</a></strong> in class projects is exciting.</li>
  <li>and of course, source control with git and Github.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="this-week">This Week</h2>
<p>The first week of class has been mostly introductory. Most of the time I’ve spent on setting up this blog. I initially set up the blog with Jekyll Now on Github Pages.</p>

<p>While it was working great I’ve ended up with a different setup and theme:</p>

<p>I’m using <strong><a href="https://github.com/biomadeira/jasper">Jasper</a></strong>, a Jekyll adaptation of one Casper, the default theme of my favourite blog platform, <a href="https://ghost.org/">Ghost</a> (check it out, it’s great and not Wordpress!). This required me to hook up the repo to my Travis-CI account. The Travis-CI script generates the HTML files and pushes them to the <code class="highlighter-rouge">gh-pages</code> branch. The reason why this is necessary is because Github doesn’t allow plugins when deploying with Github Pages for security reasons (the theme makes use of Ruby gems and scripts to build the pages).</p>

<p>Here are the advantages of this setup, and why I think it’s great despite the overhead work involved:</p>

<ul>
  <li>No need to set up any hosting, as Github Pages can easily host it.</li>
  <li>The theme is minimalistic, content-focused and without frills.</li>
  <li>I can still push Markdown files to the repo to publish.</li>
  <li>I got to use Travis-CI in advance, which will be useful in a few week when I will have to use it for projects.</li>
</ul>

<p>Here are some takeaways from this:</p>

<ul>
  <li>To publish a project website on Github Pages, you can create a branch called <code class="highlighter-rouge">gh-pages</code>.</li>
  <li>I’ve always been using <code class="highlighter-rouge">git</code> with the terminal. I’ve started using a GUI (<a href="https://www.git-tower.com/">Tower for Mac</a>), and it’s great. It’s not as cool as using the terminal, but it saves time and it gets the job done, which is what matters.</li>
  <li>You’re required to generate a secure token to put in your <code class="highlighter-rouge">.travis.yml</code> file to get Travis-CI to properly run.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="next-week">Next Week</h2>
<p>I am aiming to set up my development environment next. This will involve setting up my Docker container from the class image, to run a VM with all required components.</p>

<p>I’ll also change my DNS setting of my domain, so that this blog can be accessed on my personal domain.</p>

<p>I also plan on doing more independent work with C++. I have used Java and C before, so conceptually I should be able to grasp it, but it will take some practice to get used to the syntax.
Hopefully, I will be soon able to start practicing interview questions (implementation of algorithms and data structures) with C++.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
