<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>gvsi.github.io/cs371p/</title>
   
   <link>http://gvsi.github.io/cs371p/</link>
   <description>A blog with my progress with CS371p at UT Austin</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> Giovanni Alcantara</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Final Week</title>
	  <link>/cs371p//final-week</link>
	  <author>Giovanni Alcantara</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-12-04T22:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/cs371p//final-week</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h2 id="final-thoughts">Final thoughts</h2>
<p>After Thursday’s final exam, my first exchange semester at UT Austin is coming to a close. It’s been an incredible ride, and part of this is thanks for Prof. Downing’s OOP class.
This course was not easy, but that’s what made it incredibly rewarding at the end. Learning details of C++ and proper Object-Oriented design seems like a trival task, but it’s what I believe will set apart successful software engineers in the industry.
The final exam was not as bad as I expected–I panicked a bit going through the questions, but keeping a calm attitude, I did manage to tackle each problem. These were testing topics ranging from inherance, to design pattern design (singleton) and general C++ classes implementation.
Prof. Downing is easily one of the best professor I’ve ever had. He showed incredible passion, combined with his  great understanding of the subject and an entrenched desire to shape the next generation of successful software engineers. He strives to make his courses industry-oriented, with a focus on using the standard tools currently in use in companies’ development workflows.
Overall, this was a great course, and would highly recommend it to anyone doing a Computer Science/Software Engineering degree.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Week 13</title>
	  <link>/cs371p//week-thirteen</link>
	  <author>Giovanni Alcantara</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-11-19T23:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/cs371p//week-thirteen</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h2 id="what-did-i-do-this-past-week">What did I do this past week?</h2>
<p>Earlier this week I wrapped things up with Life, and finally turned the last project in. It feels very satisfying to submit the last assignment, though Test #2 is just a couple of weeks away.
In class we covered more details about inheritance, reviewed dynamic binding and the <code class="highlighter-rouge">virtual</code> keyword, and saw the motivation behind the use of abstract classes compared to concrete inheritance.</p>

<h2 id="whats-in-my-way">What’s in my way?</h2>
<p>Exams. Luck wanted me to have three exams scheduled on Thursday, December 1st. And that includes Object-Oriented Programming. If I don’t start revising during the Thanksgiving break, it will be bad.</p>

<h2 id="what-will-i-do-next-week">What will I do next week?</h2>
<p>Enjoy a break, and start revising.</p>

<h2 id="tip-of-the-week">Tip of the week</h2>
<p><a href="http://sleepyti.me/">sleepyti.me</a> helps you calculate the best time to set your morning alarm, so that you wake up in between sleep cycles.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Week 12</title>
	  <link>/cs371p//week-twelve</link>
	  <author>Giovanni Alcantara</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-11-12T23:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/cs371p//week-twelve</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h2 id="what-did-i-do-this-past-week">What did I do this past week?</h2>
<p>This past week I started and almost completed the last project with my partner. It did not go as smoothly as it did with Darwin, but we got it working at the end. We got stuck in the allocation of the cells in the heap, but besides that, the implementation was quite straightforward. We’re planning on writing unit tests early next week.</p>

<p>In class, we finally covered the core part of the Object-Oriented language paradigm: inheritance. I find it amusing how it’s Week 11 and we’re barely scratching OOP concepts in class. I feel that most of our time spent in class focuses on C++ minutiae and details. I actually don’t mind this, and do think that it will come in useful when working in the industry.</p>

<h2 id="whats-in-my-way">What’s in my way?</h2>
<p>Not much has been in my way lately.</p>

<h2 id="what-will-i-do-next-week">What will I do next week?</h2>
<p>Next week I’ll be wrapping things up with Life, and hopefully start revising for the final test.</p>

<h2 id="tip-of-the-week">Tip of the week</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.meteor.com/">Meteor</a> is an amazing full-stack Javascript framework. It’s amazing for fast prototyping. I’ve used it for two big-scale web applications now, and I could not recommend it enough if you want to build quick, reactive, scalable web apps.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Week 11</title>
	  <link>/cs371p//week-eleven</link>
	  <author>Giovanni Alcantara</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-11-07T11:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/cs371p//week-eleven</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h2 id="what-did-i-do-this-past-week">What did I do this past week?</h2>
<p>This week we finished our custom implementation of vector by integrating the concept of rvalue references in the parameters of the constructor and the copy assignment. We also discussed how we can cast variables to rvalues with the use of the <code class="highlighter-rouge">move</code> semantics.</p>

<p>We then covered the different types of variables in C++ (local, global, class and their static counterparts).</p>

<p>This weekend has been intense! I participated to the <a href="3daystartup.org">3 Day Startup</a> program. My idea (<a href="mentuit.com">Mentuit</a>) was selected as one of the projects of the weekend, and I got to work on it with other talented students. I didn’t much sleep, but it was an incredibly rewarding experience, and I definitely recommend it to anyone interested in startups and entrepreneurship.</p>

<h2 id="whats-in-my-way">What’s in my way?</h2>
<p>Lack of sleep. I need to recover from this weekend. Hopefully, I’ll be fully recovered in a couple of days.</p>

<h2 id="what-will-i-do-next-week">What will I do next week?</h2>
<p>Start working on Life.</p>

<h2 id="tip-of-the-week">Tip of the week</h2>
<p><a href="3daystartup.org">3 Day Startup</a>, seriously, check it out! They hold many events in different cities. Also, it all started here in Austin, TX, and it’s now an international movement!</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Week 10</title>
	  <link>/cs371p//week-ten</link>
	  <author>Giovanni Alcantara</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-10-29T21:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/cs371p//week-ten</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h2 id="what-did-i-do-this-past-week">What did I do this past week?</h2>
<p>It baffles my mind that this was Week 10 of Fall 2016. It feels like a few days ago that I started my exchange year abroad at UT.</p>

<p>This week has been relatively easy. Not much going on, apart from introduction to the next project, Darwin. We had one talk on Wednesday from UTCS alumni at Pariveda, and an event for UTCS 50th Anniversary was running on Thursday, which led to class being cancelled.</p>

<p>I started the Darwin project with my partner, and despite having only met once so far and for only a few hours, I think we have a good understanding of the requirements, we have laid out our idea for the software architecture that we want to have in place, and have set plans to meet this weekend.</p>

<h2 id="whats-in-my-way">What’s in my way?</h2>
<p>Course registrations. Courses I want to take next semester are closed/waitlisted. Despite being a junior, my first registration day is very late because I’m an exchange student and do not have UT credits (from which the schedule is based on) except for the ones of this semester. So, for registration purposes, I’m a freshman. Hopefully my advisor will be able to help me out.</p>

<h2 id="what-will-i-do-next-week">What will I do next week?</h2>
<p>I’ll work on Darwin and register for classes.</p>

<h2 id="tip-of-the-week">Tip of the week</h2>
<p><a href="cmhc.utexas.edu">UT Counseling and Mental Health Center</a>. Mental health is incredibly important, and the people at CMHC are doing a great job! Check them out if you simply need someone to talk to or are going through a difficult period.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Week 9</title>
	  <link>/cs371p//week-nine</link>
	  <author>Giovanni Alcantara</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-10-23T16:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/cs371p//week-nine</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h2 id="what-did-i-do-this-past-week">What did I do this past week?</h2>
<p>This week I finished the Allocator project (I was done with the coding part very early, but put off writing the unit tests until the end). In class we finished our custom implementation of <code class="highlighter-rouge">vector</code>, which seemed straightforward.</p>

<p>This week has been surprisingly productive for me. It’s not academic productivity, however. I figured out the final details of a project I’d been working the last few months, and I launched it this weekend!</p>

<p><a href="http://mentuit.com">Mentuit</a> is an online platform that connects to motivated individuals to experts in particular fields, and helps them develop a mentoring relationship.</p>

<p>The problem I am trying to solve is that it’s difficult, yet critically important nowadays, to have access to mentors that can open doors for you. I want to build a great community and network of mentors and mentees with Mentuit.</p>

<h2 id="whats-in-my-way">What’s in my way?</h2>
<p>Not much has been in my way.</p>

<h2 id="what-will-i-do-next-week">What will I do next week?</h2>
<p>Next week I’ll try to get started on the Darwin project.</p>

<h2 id="tip-of-the-week">Tip of the week</h2>
<p><a href="http://mentuit.com">Mentuit</a>, check it out! You can sign up as a mentor, mentee, or both if you want! I would also appreciate your feedback!</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Week 8</title>
	  <link>/cs371p//week-eight</link>
	  <author>Giovanni Alcantara</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-10-15T22:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/cs371p//week-eight</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h2 id="what-did-i-do-this-past-week">What did I do this past week?</h2>
<p>This week I started working on the Allocator project. I haven’t done much in terms of coding yet, as setting up the infrastructure took me a while. Hopefully I will be finished by the end of the weekend.</p>

<p>In class we covered some aspects of arrays in C++, we clarified some details about the heap and the stack, and started exploring the implementation of vectors.</p>

<h2 id="whats-in-my-way">What’s in my way?</h2>
<p>The two CS projects due next week are my priority at the moment. I always hope for a smooth progress with coding projects, but eventually always end up being stuck somewhere. That’s part of learning, clearly, but I hate when it happens. And I hate knowing that it will happen, whether I want it or not.</p>

<h2 id="what-will-i-do-next-week">What will I do next week?</h2>
<p>Next week I’ll be working on CS projects and a presentation for a startup competition.</p>

<h2 id="tip-of-the-week">Tip of the week</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.pexels.com">Pexels</a>, a site with beautiful, free stock images.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Week 7</title>
	  <link>/cs371p//week-seven</link>
	  <author>Giovanni Alcantara</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-10-08T11:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/cs371p//week-seven</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h2 id="what-did-i-do-this-past-week">What did I do this past week?</h2>
<p>This week we covered more C++ concepts and minutiae in the wake of last Thursday’s test.</p>

<p>We learned about a few types of new pointers in C++, originating from the combination of the concept of constants with the ones of pointer. So, we have now four new types of pointers differing in the immutable nature of either the pointer or of what the pointer is pointing to.</p>

<p>We also saw some ways in which C++ caches constants in memory. If we have <code class="highlighter-rouge">const char* a = "abc"</code> and <code class="highlighter-rouge">const char* b = "abc"</code>, then <code class="highlighter-rouge">assert(a == b)</code>.</p>

<p>The test itself was manageable, though I’m unsure about my implementation of the custom C++ iterator.</p>

<h2 id="whats-in-my-way">What’s in my way?</h2>
<p>Last week I received a summer internship offer from Salesforce (if you’ve been an intern with them in the past, please, get in touch–I’d love to hear your experience!).
Now, two other companies have decided to schedule interviews next week because of the deadline of my first offer. While I’m grateful that they try to accommodate me, it’s looking like it will be stressful week coming up.</p>

<h2 id="what-will-i-do-next-week">What will I do next week?</h2>
<p>Mostly interview prep, and prepare for my Management exam.</p>

<h2 id="tip-of-the-week">Tip of the week</h2>
<p>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pomodoro_Technique">Pomodoro Technique</a> is time management framework that helps me be more productive. You can use a simple timer on your phone, but there are apps that are specifically designed for this purpose. I’m using <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/be-focused-pro-focus-timer/id961632517?mt=12">this one</a> for macOS.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Week 6</title>
	  <link>/cs371p//week-six</link>
	  <author>Giovanni Alcantara</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-10-01T11:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/cs371p//week-six</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h2 id="what-did-i-do-this-past-week">What did I do this past week?</h2>
<p>This week we covered more C++ topics. It’s starting to get very hairy with all the funny syntax and behaviors that C++ can exhibit.</p>

<p>I’ve tried going through the examples we covered in class and running similar ones on my machine. I still did very poorly on the last quiz, which covered the execution of different types of constructors.</p>

<p>So here’s a breakdown of what we learned this week:</p>

<ul>
  <li>iterators and their behavior in different contexts</li>
  <li>refinement overwriting</li>
  <li>constructors</li>
  <li>friends</li>
  <li>that friends can touch each other privates</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="whats-in-my-way">What’s in my way?</h2>
<p>Exam 1 is coming up next week. I have two other exams next week, as well as regular weekly project deadlines, and will need to really schedule my time properly.</p>

<h2 id="what-will-i-do-next-week">What will I do next week?</h2>
<p>Mostly try to survive. I have started following my review schedule two days ago, and I’m not falling behind yet!</p>

<h2 id="tip-of-the-week">Tip of the week</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.hackerrank.com/domains/tutorials/cracking-the-coding-interview">Hackerrank’s Cracking the Coding Interview Challenges</a> has just been published. It contains videos on interview techniques that the author of CTCI filmed, as well as a collection of problems that you can solve on Hackerrank’s online IDE.</p>

<p>Also, O’Reilly has just published list of free ebooks that you can download online. Here’s the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/learnprogramming/comments/556kxj/oreilly_offering_programming_ebooks_for_free/">list</a>.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Week 5</title>
	  <link>/cs371p//week-five</link>
	  <author>Giovanni Alcantara</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-09-24T16:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/cs371p//week-five</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h2 id="what-did-i-do-this-past-week">What did I do this past week?</h2>
<p>This week I have wrapped things up with Netflix, and proceeded to close that dark chapter of my time at UT where frustration often took over my sanity.</p>

<p>I learned different things by working on the Netflix project:</p>

<ul>
  <li>C++ should not be at top of your list for machine learning,</li>
  <li>Serialization is great if it works,</li>
  <li>Having an isolated development environment/container like Docker is great if you can get everything set up in it,</li>
  <li>Don’t share a single Travis-CI worker with 160 more people, running computationally expensive jobs.</li>
</ul>

<p>Besides reflecting on Netflix, this week we explored some more C++ concepts, including the different types of iterators and the whole notion of function definition with the weakest possible iterator. We had also had an illuminating talk about software development at JPL.</p>

<p>I’ve also been to the CNS Career Fair on Tuesday and it was a great opportunity to talk to employers and getting to know the companies that they were representing.</p>

<h2 id="whats-in-my-way">What’s in my way?</h2>
<p>Lack of time is on my way. Interviewing for internships while taking a full load of courses requires a great deal of prioritizing and compromising. It hasn’t been too bad though.</p>

<h2 id="what-will-i-do-next-week">What will I do next week?</h2>
<p>Next week I’ll make a plan to review for tests and exams.</p>

<h2 id="tip-of-the-week">Tip of the week</h2>
<p><a href="https://hadoop.apache.org/">Hadoop</a>. We talked about MapReduce in class, and if you’re really interested in distributed computation, you should consider learning the framework inspired by the work at Google. Also, I’m taking a Big Data Programming class which teaches Hadoop and Spark this semester, and you should check that out as well.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
