<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>gvsi.github.io/cs371p/</title>
   
   <link>http://gvsi.github.io/cs371p/</link>
   <description>A blog with my progress with CS371p at UT Austin</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> Giovanni Alcantara</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Week 7</title>
	  <link>/cs371p//week-seven</link>
	  <author>Giovanni Alcantara</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-10-08T11:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/cs371p//week-seven</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h2 id="what-did-i-do-this-past-week">What did I do this past week?</h2>
<p>This week we covered more C++ concepts and minutiae in the wake of last Thursday’s test.</p>

<p>We learned about a few types of new pointers in C++, originating from the combination of the concept of constants with the ones of pointer. So, we have now four new types of pointers differing in the immutable nature of either the pointer or of what the pointer is pointing to.</p>

<p>We also saw some ways in which C++ caches constants in memory. If we have <code class="highlighter-rouge">const char* a = "abc"</code> and <code class="highlighter-rouge">const char* b = "abc"</code>, then <code class="highlighter-rouge">assert(a == b)</code>.</p>

<p>The test itself was manageable, though I’m unsure about my implementation of the custom C++ iterator.</p>

<h2 id="whats-in-my-way">What’s in my way?</h2>
<p>Last week I received a summer internship offer from Salesforce (if you’ve been an intern with them in the past, please, get in touch–I’d love to hear your experience!).
Now, two other companies have decided to schedule interviews next week because of the deadline of my first offer. While I’m grateful that they try to accommodate me, it’s looking like it will be stressful week coming up.</p>

<h2 id="what-will-i-do-next-week">What will I do next week?</h2>
<p>Mostly interview prep, and prepare for my Management exam.</p>

<h2 id="tip-of-the-week">Tip of the week</h2>
<p>The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pomodoro_Technique">Pomodoro Technique</a> is time management framework that helps me be more productive. You can use a simple timer on your phone, but there are apps that are specifically designed for this purpose. I’m using <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/be-focused-pro-focus-timer/id961632517?mt=12">this one</a> for macOS.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
