<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>gvsi.github.io/cs371p/</title>
   
   <link>http://gvsi.github.io/cs371p/</link>
   <description>A blog with my progress with CS371p at UT Austin</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> Giovanni Alcantara</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Week 6</title>
	  <link>/cs371p//week-six</link>
	  <author>Giovanni Alcantara</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-10-01T11:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/cs371p//week-six</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h2 id="what-did-i-do-this-past-week">What did I do this past week?</h2>
<p>This week we covered more C++ topics. It’s starting to get very hairy with all the funny syntax and behaviors that C++ can exhibit.</p>

<p>I’ve tried going through the examples we covered in class and running similar ones on my machine. I still did very poorly on the last quiz, which covered the execution of different types of constructors.</p>

<p>So here’s a breakdown of what we learned this week:</p>

<ul>
  <li>iterators and their behavior in different contexts</li>
  <li>refinement overwriting</li>
  <li>constructors</li>
  <li>friends</li>
  <li>that friends can touch each other privates</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="whats-in-my-way">What’s in my way?</h2>
<p>Exam 1 is coming up next week. I have two other exams next week, as well as regular weekly project deadlines, and will need to really schedule my time properly.</p>

<h2 id="what-will-i-do-next-week">What will I do next week?</h2>
<p>Mostly try to survive. I have started following my review schedule two days ago, and I’m not falling behind yet!</p>

<h2 id="tip-of-the-week">Tip of the week</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.hackerrank.com/domains/tutorials/cracking-the-coding-interview">Hackerrank’s Cracking the Coding Interview Challenges</a> has just been published. It contains videos on interview techniques that the author of CTCI filmed, as well as a collection of problems that you can solve on Hackerrank’s online IDE.</p>

<p>Also, O’Reilly has just published list of free ebooks that you can download online. Here’s the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/learnprogramming/comments/556kxj/oreilly_offering_programming_ebooks_for_free/">list</a>.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
